

CONTACT

+57 318 389 7929



giraldosofia481@gmail.com



Medellín, Colombia



https://github.com/ysgiraldo

LANGUAGES

Spanish / English

SOFT SKILLS

Leadership

Teamwork

Strategic thinking

STACK

Python Postgres Django

HTML CSS Dash

Excel Azure

Yackelin Sofía Giraldo Castaño

Data Scientist - Economist

ABOUT ME

Data scientist with a degree in Economics and currently pursuing a specialization in Analytics, with experience in data analytics and Backend and Frontend development.

Characterized by being a responsible, dedicated, proactive person, with great abilities for teamwork and leadership, as well as passionate about new learning and professional growth.

EXPERIENCE

Aug 2023 - Currently

Talent B - Analytics

Grupo

Bancolombia

I develop web pages that facilitate interaction with the client from the backend to the frontend, using analytics and data collection with the use of Python, Django, Dash,

Excel, HTML and CSS.

Jan 2023 - Jul 2023

Analytics Intern

Grupo Éxito

I developed analytical models using R, Python, SQL and facilitating the entity's decision-making processes and in research with Banco de la República.

Feb 2022 - Nov 2022

Research assistant

University of Medellin

I carried out activities related to analytics and data collection using tools such as R, Python and Excel on

behavioral economics and financial models.

EDUCATION

Jan 2024 - Currently

Specialization in Analytics

National university of Colombia

Jan 2019 - Jun 2023

Economist

University of Medellin

SOME PROJECTS

Leader

Development of Web App for bank user interaction - Grupo Bancolombia

Market Share Forecasts - Grupo Éxito

Co-Author

Determinants of the exchange rate in Colombia - University of Medellín